# Golden Ogbeka



ogbekagolden@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/goldenogbeka



+2348169200454



https://goldenogbeka.vercel.app/

## Summary

I have over 5 years experience in building production level web and mobile applications in agriculture, real estate, finance, logistics, food and retail service sectors.

I am passionate about providing solutions to people using technology and look forward to the growth and development of everyone I come across

# **Experience**



#### Frontend Engineer

Alerzo

Oct 2022 - Present (6 months)

Worked on Veedez website and admin platforms.

Also worked on the internal admin application for Veedez

# Full Stack Developer

#### **KEYLA**

Oct 2021 - Oct 2022 (1 year 1 month)

- I created a brand website for Cravings Logistics
- I worked on upgrading Cravings website into a full E-commerce application
- I re-developed the company's website (www.keyla.ng) using React JS and Gatsby
- I replicated the UI Design for the food vendor applications' website called Cravings (www.cravingsng.com) and ensured mobile responsiveness and a great user experience using React JS and Material UI
- I developed an admin dashboard for a another food vendor application with total user and admin management using ReactJS, Material UI and React's Context API
- I completed the backend of a food delivery app that has a full logistics feature using PostgreSQL, NodeJS and ExpressJS.

#### Full Stack Developer

Composite Property Development

Feb 2021 - Dec 2021 (11 months)

I completed four main tasks in this role

- I rebranded the companies website and created User Interface Designs with Figma. Then I created the backend for the application using MySQL, NodeJs and ExpressJS
- My team and I created the frontend of a crowdfunding real estate application that would be used by the company with ReactJS, Material UI and Reacts' Context API
- My team and I concluded the company's staff portal and client dashboard to manage company's inventory, projects, staff, clients and contractors
- My team and I organized a training session for the staff of the company to train them on how to use the application we developed



#### Full stack Developer and Product Owner

The Chicken Universe

Oct 2019 - Jan 2021 (1 year 4 months)

I created this application to help connect buyers and sellers of chicken products together. As the only developer involved in the projects, I:

- Created the web application using React JS, EJS, NodeJS, Express JS, MongoDB, Sockets IO and React's Context API
- I hosted the web application using cloud hosting and was in charge of managing the SSH interactions
- I created the mobile application using React Native and hosted it on Amazon's AppStore



#### Network Technician and User Support

Bank of Industry Limited

Feb 2017 - Aug 2017 (7 months)

Prior to this role, I had worked in an internet café and was used to interacting with customers and addressing their needs but this role taught me about utilizing this skill in a corporate setup. I was taught problem solving patterns as I handled staff complaints that were related to technological devices and network infrastructure issues

### **Education**



#### Covenant University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science

2014 - 2018

I was taught the basics, history and essence of computer science, software design and architecture and was awarded with First Class Honors

### **Licenses & Certifications**



Diploma in Leadership Developement - African Leadership Development Centre



🗼 Jobberman Soft-Skills Training - Jobberman Nigeria

3449602



The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing - Grow with Google Africa

TJ5 EV9 Q4K

The Complete JavaScript Course: Beginner to Advanced level by Farda Karimov

- Udemy

UC-85aae5c4-8ce5-497f-bc15-36062b9b2714

### SEO Certified - HubSpot Academy

fdcca20413d44bda969859eb4c6cc319

- **Digital Nigeria Certification Courses** Microsoft
- Covenant University Alumni Association Mentorship Program Covenant University Alumni Association (CUALA)
- Content Marketing HubSpot Academy Issued Aug 2021 - Expires Sep 2023 c0636358d07248f6b66c7439af5311e3
- AWS Technical Essentials Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- **Master Course in Project Management 2.0** Udemy UC-427a3f24-d2a0-4a22-9891-0411c757eb65

#### **Skills**

React.js • Front-End Development • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • Search Engine Optimization (SEO) • React Native • Technical Support • Node.js • Full-Stack Development • Software Development • JavaScript

#### **Honors & Awards**

Employee of the month - Keyla
Apr 2022